# **Dustin Cremascoli**

Mount Prospect, IL, 60056 | (619) 840-1991 dustincremascoli@aol.com

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

Expertise in Core Python and Computer Science principles. Advanced knowledge of SQL. Mastery in data mining, modeling, and reporting analytics on large data sets. Experience in critical financial and performance metrics-(P&L management, ROI, descriptive statistics).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Finance and Analytics Manager**

Oct 2015 - Present

SYW Financial Services(Transformco LLC), Chicago, IL

- · Reporting, profit analysis, forecasting, and planning for Layaway and Leasing businesses within SYW Financial Services formats. Consistently collaborate with the leadership team in monitoring and addressing any issues related to the financial performance of these payment options.
- · Ensure corporate financial controls exist within the Financial Services business. Provide ad hoc reporting and analysis as needed to help drive positive results, providing analytics support using Database (SQL) expertise.

# **Business Finance Manager**

Dec 2013 - Oct 2015

Sears & Kmart Sporting Goods, Chicago, IL

- · Full responsibility for planning (both high level and unit), forecasting, analysis, reporting, and ensuring controls are in place for all Sporting Goods categories within the Sears and Kmart formats. Routinely partner with the Business Unit CFO and leadership team in monitoring and addressing any issues related to the financial performance for these supported categories.
- · Partner in business and line reviews with the buying teams and senior management.
- · Consistently manage the markdown review and approval process.

#### **Data and Analytics Manager**

Sep 2010 - Dec 2013

Sears Hometown & Outlet, Chicago, IL

- · Developed and implemented analytic tools that support the business planning processes; initiating and overseeing business transforming initiatives from concept, through testing, to final implementation.
- · Initiated new insight development efforts toward identification/development of new data sources to applying new insight development approaches to existing data.
- · Maintain and improved existing informational tools to increase business transparency and profitability.

#### **Senior Financial Analyst**

Jan 2007 - Sep 2010

Sears Off-Mall

- · Recipient of the SHC Finance "Make More Money" Award. Developed numerous reports to help the Off-Mall business units discuss results with senior leadership teams. These reports included transaction value reporting and district region comp sales reporting.
- · Led cross-functional teams to ensure the proper development of store plans as part of the annual planning cycle for the Grand's, Hardware, and Hometown store formats. Developed,

refined, and loaded profit and loss statement plans into Essbase (financial system) for approximately 1,100 store locations.

### **Business Intelligence Analyst**

Jun 2000 - Jan 2007

The Great Indoors, Chicago, IL

- · Created and implemented an automated database model to efficiently price all clearance merchandise (approximately 9 million dollars of inventory quarterly.) The primary goals of the process were to liquidate clearance merchandise within a six-month timeframe while minimizing gross profit deterioration.
- · Responsible for successfully planning and forecasting sales for all TGI merchandise businesses (yearly sales of over 500 million dollars.)

# First Assistant Coach-Men's Volleyball

Jan 1998 - Jun 2000

Lovola University Chicago, Chicago, IL

· Led and directed Division I level athletes in multiple areas, including sports-specific skills and fundamentals, training methods, and game preparation.

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Arts (M.Ed)

Sep 2000 - Jun 2006

Loyola University Chicago, Chicago, IL

**Bachelor of Science (B.S.)** 

Sep 1993 - Jun 1998

San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

### **PCAP – Certified Associate in Python Programming**

2021

Python Institute - PCAP-31-03

IBM Data Science 2020

IBM on Coursera